goodguide.com 2016-05-17

# Privacy Policy | GoodGuide

## Your Privacy

GoodGuide offers products and services that include our website at goodguide.com as well as our browser toolbars, mobile applications, and APIs (collectively, the “Services”). GoodGuide knows that you care about how your personal information is collected, used and shared so we take many steps to protect your privacy. This document (the “Privacy Policy”) sets forth our practices and policies with respect to our collection, use and sharing of personal information through your use of the Services. Your use of the Services constitutes acknowledgement that that you have read this Privacy Policy and accept its terms. Please do not use the Services if you do not want the Privacy Policy to apply to you.

### What Does This Privacy Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy covers treatment of information that GoodGuide may gather when you access or use the Services. This Privacy Policy does not apply to sites or services owned, operated or controlled by third parties. Information that you provide to such third parties and their sites or services will be subject to the privacy policies of such sites or services.

### What Information Does GoodGuide Collect?

We divide the information that we collect into two categories for the purpose of this Privacy Policy:

  1. The first category is personally identifiable information (“PII”) - information that can identify you as an individual. Examples of PII are names, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses or your account credentials at third-party e-commerce sites.
  2. The other category is “everything else” — that is, information that is not PII, and cannot identify you as an individual. Examples of this category would be page views (of company or product ratings), products scanned (and their geographic location), interactions on GoodGuide or third-party websites (such as recommends/avoids or product additions to shopping carts), and any statistical or aggregate information. We have implemented Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising (Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting). You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings or NAI’s consumer opt-out. In addition, you can use the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on to disable tracking by Google Analytics. We will use the data provided by Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to develop the site and content around our users’ interests.

GoodGuide is able to provide product and company sustainability ratings free to consumers through the display of advertising on our site. We use Google’s Doubleclick for Advertisers to serve our ads, and some advertisers also collect information through Neilsen. You can read more about how Google and Neilsen use data collected on GoodGuide, and how to control the information you share by clicking these links: [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) and [www.nielsen.com/us/en/privacy-policy/digital-measurement](http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/privacy-policy/digital-measurement.html). You can also select not to share your data for interest-based advertising by opting out here: [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

We use both types of information to provide the Services. This allows us to personalize and improve the services we offer to you. The following gives a little more background on both categories of information:

**Information You Provide to Us.** Provision of PII is not required to use the Services and review product or company ratings. However, in order to use certain Services or to access the full features of certain Services you may be required to register with us (and give us PII such as your name and email address) or provide your account credentials at third-party e-commerce sites. You can choose not to provide us with such PII, but then you will not be able to use or take advantage of some of the Services. For example, only registered users can access reports summarizing their product searches or scanning activity. Similarly, only users who provide e-commerce account credentials can have their purchase histories at such sites automatically evaluated by GoodGuide.

The information, including PII, that you provide is also used to customize the content you see and to communicate with you about our Services and new products. If you provide PII to us through one of our Services, we may use it for these purposes in connection with other Services; for example, if you provide your email address to us in connection with a GoodGuide Service you are giving us permission to use that email address in order to respond to your requests, advise you about other services, and so forth. We provide account management tools that let you manage your subscription status to GoodGuide email communications.

**Information Collected Automatically.** We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with the Services. GoodGuide automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser or mobile device, including your IP address or mobile location, cookie information, and the page or portion of the Services that you requested.

GoodGuide also automatically tracks users’ interactions with the Services (whether through use of our websites, mobile applications, browser toolbars or other products or services). These interactions include product or brand searches or scans, user-submitted content contributions (e.g., recommendations/avoids or comments), social media activity (e.g. shares/likes) or e-commerce activity (e.g., additions to shopping carts and checkouts). Registered users are provided with password-restricted access to their own activity data and GoodGuide also uses these data to personalize our Services for you. Any other use of automatically collected information occurs only in aggregate form, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. Automatically collected and aggregated data enables GoodGuide to understand how users are accessing and using the Services so that we can improve them and focus our efforts on popular features.

### Will GoodGuide Share the Information it Collects?

**Personally Identifiable Information.** GoodGuide does not rent, sell, or share PII about you with other companies for any purpose. While we do not rent, share, or sell PII to advertisers, we may utilize PII within our systems to customize the delivery of marketing content or product promotions that will be of greatest relevance, value, and interest to you.

**Aggregate Information.** GoodGuide may share aggregate non-PII information with others to help improve the Services, and third party services and products.

**Contractors.** GoodGuide may contract with other companies (e.g., for data analysis, email services or other specialties) to perform tasks on our behalf. We may need (and you are authorizing us) to share your information, including PII, with them for the limited purpose of allowing us to fulfill these tasks. We bind these contractors to agreements that prohibit them from using or disclosing any information they receive from GoodGuide for any purposes except the ones they are hired to provide to us.

**Legal Compliance.** GoodGuide reserves the right to disclose your PII when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to (1) comply with the law; (2) enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; (3) or protect the rights, property or safety of GoodGuide, our employees, our users, or others.

**Business Transfers.** If a third party acquires GoodGuide or GoodGuide goes out of business through bankruptcy or otherwise, information would be one of the assets that could be transferred to or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of GoodGuide may continue to use all information, including PII, as long as it does so only as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

### How Secure is My Information?

GoodGuide has put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures in an effort to safeguard our Services, help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and use the PII we collect from you in compliance with this privacy policy. When communicating with third-party e-commerce sites, GoodGuide transmits information such as your Account Credentials securely.

### Can I Access or Change My Information?

As a registered user, we will provide you with a password-protected personal account, where you can maintain your profile. It is your responsibility to select an appropriate password for this account, to change it regularly and to ensure that your password is not disclosed to others.

Automatically gathered and aggregated information cannot generally be reviewed or changed by individuals. As noted, such information does not link to any PII about you.

### How Do You Use Cookies and Similar Tools?

GoodGuide uses cookies and similar tools to track session data and allow us to personalize your experience of the Services. We do not use cookies or other tools to collect or reveal PII to GoodGuide. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, or erasing existing cookies. If you elect to turn off cookies, GoodGuide will not be able to store cookies on your system or collect information from them. As a result, you will not be able to use the personalized features of the Services that depend on cookies and the information they contain.

Some of our advertisers may use cookies in the content they provide for publication within the GoodGuide Services, as may the owners of websites or other services where our Services are available. For example, the GoodGuide browser toolbar operates when you visit e-commerce websites. GoodGuide has no access to or control over the use of cookies by any advertisers or owners of third-party websites or other services.

### Other Sites and Services

The Services may contain links or otherwise make it possible for you to access other websites and services. These other sites and services are not owned or controlled by GoodGuide. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites or services.

### What if You Change the Privacy Policy?

This Privacy Policy is a living document. GoodGuide may amend the Privacy Policy as we add new features to the Services, or as the law or circumstances change. Accordingly, we reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make material changes to the Privacy Policy we will post those changes here and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of the changes. Use of particular information or PII will remain subject to whatever version of the Privacy Policy was in effect at the time it was collected.

### Questions or Concerns

If you have any questions, concerns or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, the Services, or GoodGuide in general please contact us at [info@goodguide.com](mailto:info@goodguide.com).
